Tejas Hegde

H.72, Block No 12, Dandeli, Karnataka, 9742827993 tejasl

tejashegde.1595@gmail.com

Enthusiastic and dedicated professional with experience of 2 years and 7 months on cloud solutions using Java and .Net. Experienced in building MVC and SOA Web Apps in JAVA along with active interest and experience in client-side frontend technologies. Seeking a job role with an opportunity for professional challenges, thus improving my ability to solve problems in an effective and creative manner. Presently pursuing PG Diploma from IIIT-B on Full Stack Web Development thus enhancing the existing working knowledge in Web Development.

Professional Experience (2 years, 7 months)

SONY INDIA SOFTWARE CENTER(BANGALORE)

Software Engineer, Aug 2018 - Present

Claimant Conversion from hard copies to Digitized form (Sony Pictures) – 1 year 5 months

- Worked on the development of AWS Cloud Solution to convert the hard copy claimants to a digitized form.
- Handled the development of Spring Boot Restful Web API's by using efficient design principles for transacting the digitized data present in the Postgres Database using JPA.
- Handled the development and interaction of services using Spring Cloud and Netflix Eureka thus reducing the effort of maintainability and coupling.
- Worked on the implementation of Authentication schemes such as Basic and Bearer using JWT tokens thus maintaining the standards and security for application access.
- Exposed to writing efficient and optimized stored procedures and functions for the background processes in Relational Databases.
- Experienced in handling unit testing using Junit, Mockito.
- Experienced in version control tools like GIT and application management tools like Docker.

Data Aggregation and Reporting (Sony Pictures) - 8 months

- Worked on a Data Aggregation Cloud solution in Sony Pictures hosted on Microsoft Azure
- Handled the development of the User Interface built using Angular 8 by successfully integrating the REST APIs built in .NET providing hassle free UI experience to the users.
- Experienced in building dynamic SPA in both Angular and REACT with sound knowledge on Document Object Model and DOM Functions.
- Experienced in building cross browser applications with Material-UI and Bootstrap.
- Experienced in using SAAS applications of Azure like Azure Functions, Azure Logic Apps along with working knowledge on ETL Tools like Data Factory.

PG DIPLOMA IN FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT (6 MONTHS)

June 2020 – Present

- Exposure to building real time MVC applications and restful API'S in Spring Boot.
- Worked on building restful apps with Hibernate as implementation for the JPA specification.
- Exposure of using swagger specifications for building restful services along with the Authentication and Authorization knowledge on JWT Web tokens.
- Experienced with working on project management tool like Maven and also in test driven development.
- Experienced in building

Technical Skills & Expertise

- Languages: JAVA, JavaScript, C#, SQL
- Frame Works: Angular JS, React JS, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Bootstrap, REST
- Cloud Services: Azure Data Factory, Azure Logic Apps, Azure Functions, AWS Services such as ec2, Textract, Comprehend, Lambda
- Source Control: Docker, Git, VSTS
- Tools: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, IntelliJ
- Operating System: Microsoft, Unix

Education

B.V.B COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, HUBLI

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science. (2014-2018) Aggregate of 8.68 cgpa.

EXPERT PU COLLEGE, MANGALORE

PUC (12th), Physics | Chemistry | Mathematics | Statistics (2012-2014) Aggregate of 87%

ST. MICHAELS CONVENT SCHOOL

10th Class. (20012) Aggregate of 93%

Additional Skills/Recognitions

- Implementation of a POC involving the data service part of the Power apps to create a dashboard for show casing the existing projects in the company.
- Implementation of a POC involving Azure Cognitive service and angular to develop a face recognition engine.
- Developing a web application in Angular and Python to build a home page for a movie streaming application which populates the content based on user data.
- Building Single Page clone applications on REACT.

Personal Dossier

Fathers Name: Dr. R G Hegde Mothers Name: Malati Hegde

DOB: 15/19/1995 Gender: Male Passport: S4302440 Nationality: Indian

Languages: Kannada, English, Hindi